# BABATUNDE OLUWASEGUN ADEKUNLE

Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria | <u>oluwasegunababatunde@gmail.com</u> | +2348034372743

#### **PROFILE**

Reliable Employee & Software Developer with energetic and resourceful software professional with over 5 years of experience providing IT Solutions, maintenance, and managing existing software with ability to provide and IT solutions in diverse industries. Expertise in Fin-Tech services, API, database management, mobile, web, and desktop application development.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

**Freelance Agent and IT Consultant** 

March 2016 - Present

**Position: Full-Stack Software Developer** 

• Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions.

MSG System, Basel, Switzerland

**Position: Junior Software Developer** 

December 2017 - Present

Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions.

#### Elkanah IT Technologies LTD, Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria

October 2019 - Present

**Position: Full-Stack Software Developer** 

- Promptly provide maintenance for existing software solutions..
- Quickly and efficiently develop mobile, web, and desktop applications.
- Maintain reliable records by managing database data.
- Create API and library for third party to consume.

**MegaRich Consults & Networks LTD Certification of Proficiency** 

**Second Runner at NACCOSS Software Exhibition Programme** 

**NASS Overall Best Student, Computer Science** 

**NACCOSS Best Student in ND** 

• Develop financial and accounting IT solutions.

### Em&Em Info-Tech Solution, Offa, Kwara, Nigeria

August 2018 - 2019

2018

2019

2018/19

2018/19

Position: Software Developer/Instructor

- Instruct young programmers on web and desktop app development.
- Develop web and desktop applications.
- Effectively managed approximately 50 young programmers daily.

### **EDUCATION**

B.Sc, Computer Science	2021
3:60, Second Class Honour, Upper Division	
National Open University of Nigeria, Ilorin, Kwara state, Nigeria.	(2021 – Present)
ND, Computer Science	2019
3.60, Distinction Class Honors, Lower Division	
Federal Polytechnic Offa, Offa, Kwara state, Nigeria.	(2017 – 2019)
CERTIFICATION/TRAINING	
Jobberman Soft Skills Training Certification	2021

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# **ETL Foundation** - Non-Profit Organization

March 2020 - PRESENT

- Voluntarily provide basic amenities for the needy.
- Preaching the word of Christ ONLY to people for salvation of their souls.

### **HOBBIES**

- Surfing Web trends and Posting Memes.
- Analyzing Religion Concepts.
- Video Gaming.
- Skateboarding, Biking, and Hiking.
- Vacation and exploring IT Solution.

#### **SKILLS AND INTERESTS**

- Backend
- Frontend
- Library development
- Application Program Interface (API)
- Mobile, Web, and Desktop App Development
- Highly Proficient in Computer applications; (Photoshop, Corel Draw, MS Office and Other Apps)
- Interest: Training, Education, Youth Transition and Research.

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- C#.NET / VB.NET
- JAVA / KOTLIN
- XML / XAML
- ASP.NET CORE MVC / ASP.NET FRAMEWORK MVC
- ASP.NET RAZOR MVC / ASP.NET BLAZOR MVC
- Progressive Web App (PWA)
- HTML / CSS / Bootstrap / JavaScript
- MS SQL SERVER

# **Recently practicing:**

- Nodejs
- React
- MYSQL

### REFEREES

Available on request